Sean Brown 11012 N 147th E Ave Owasso, OK 74055

Email scbrown1986@gmail.com

QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

MBA with nine years aerospace engineering experience, holding positions in Design, Sustaining, and Industrial Engineering. Demonstrated project management and leadership skills. Proven ability to problem solve when faced with complex and conflicting data and priorities and to handle multiple projects at one time. Extensive process improvement and quality improvement experience. Successfully work across multifunctional areas and within cost and schedule constraints to meet company mission and objectives.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Engineer, The Nordam Group, Transparency Division, Tulsa, Oklahoma January 2016-Present, Full Time, Salaried

Project Engineer on New Product Implementation (NPI) opportunities. Role included product and process design, research and development of design and manufacturing solutions, risk analysis, product and business process improvement, project scheduling and budget, customer consultation, and root cause and corrective action management. Successfully led program teams for OEM customers such as Airbus, Airbus Helicopters, Boeing, Gulfstream, Bombardier, Embraer, FlightSafety, and Rockwell-Collins. Contributed to revenue increases of over \$10 million through several contract wins.

Led quality and process improvement project team to reduce labor and material waste in a plastic manufacturing process that resulted in a 35% reduction in scrap and a cost savings of \$440,000 a year at full production rate.

Led lessons learned and process improvement exercises to diagnose process inefficiencies, determine and develop operational best practices. Gathered data and insight from multiple sources to inform teams and management of key performance indicators and process control effectiveness. Developed process improvement solutions that reduced labor and material costs for several product lines by up to 88%.

Technical subject matter expert (SME) for internal customers, which included providing labor, material, and overall finance analysis and forecasting, writing technical proposals, and determining manufacturing feasibility, including capital expenditure and capacity requirements. Created detailed statements of work and supported short- and long-term business and strategic initiatives. Developed preliminary project schedules and budgets for NPI process requirements. Presented product and process analysis and interpretation to upper management for business review and business planning.

Engineer II, The Nordam Group, Transparency Division, Tulsa, Oklahoma November 2011 – January 2016, Full Time, Salaried

Visited technology partners to identify, review, and assess solution options. Examples include collaborating with a vision system supplier to automate transparent material inspection, reducing inspection time from 1 hour to 30 seconds, and incorporating barcode and inkjet technology into a part identification process to reduce process time from 5 minutes to 15 seconds and eliminate serial number errors.

Provided internal customer support for root cause and corrective action (RCCA) and Eight Disciplines (8D) initiatives to identify and correct recurrent business process issues. Successfully enabled process improvement via research, detailed planning, concise process requirements evaluation, benchmarking, documented work instructions, technical interviews and presentations, and detailed process testing.

Programmed and led implementation of an innovative material certification Access database to meet a need for complete visibility and traceability of material data. Database manages FAA-audited material certification data, maintains complete material traceability from raw stock material to finished product, and incorporates a material testing module for calculating material properties from Quality lab test outputs. Database has proven 100% effective preventing non-certified material from being released to Production for use in aircraft components.

Prioritized clear written communication to provide senior level reporting, showing process trends and highlighting risk indicators affecting project success. Acted as subject matter expert to lead the ideation and technical development of new products.

Lead for global team efforts using online collaboration through tools such as WebEx, Microsoft Lync, and Skype for Business.

Industrial Engineer II, The Nordam Group, Transparency Division, Tulsa, Oklahoma October 2010 – November 2011, Full Time, Salaried

Lead for process improvement implementation projects that have resulted in innovation and changes to well-established manufacturing processes. Devised a new method of forming aircraft cabin windows resulting in a 10% throughput increase with a 75% reduction in equipment footprint, an innovative solution that contributed to the procurement of a 10-year, \$6.8 million contract.

Engineer I, The Nordam Group, Interiors and Structures Division, Tulsa, Oklahoma June 2008 – October 2010, Full Time, Salaried

Visited and coordinated with customers, including Hawker Beechcraft, Learjet, Bombardier Completions Center Montreal, and Gulfstream, in dual engineering and estimating roles to support existing programs, procure new business, and develop solutions to customer requirements.

SKILLS

Aerospace Manufacturing and Design: 9 years

Technical Leadership: 8 years

• Proven ability to refine operational and technical requirements, diagnose process issues, and develop innovative solutions for internal and external customers

Project Management: 9 years

Mentorship: 6 years

Process Improvement: 9 years Quality Improvement: 9 years

Relational Databases and ERPs (Microsoft Access, SQL, SAP): 9 years

Database Management: 9 years Technical Writing: 9 years

Extensive experience documenting processes and reporting project data and solutions

Computer Programming (Visual Basic, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS): 8 years

Quantitative and Qualitative Analysis: 6 years

 Performed data gathering and qualitative analysis for process improvement initiatives. Utilized statistical analysis software, such as Minitab and Excel, to evaluate business theories and make informed process design decisions

Microsoft Products (Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, MS Project, Outlook, SharePoint, Visio): 9 years

EDUCATION

B.S. Aerospace Engineering
B.S. Mechanical Engineering
2008
Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, Oklahoma
Overall GPA 3.48

Masters of Business Administration (MBA)

2016

Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, Oklahoma GPA 4.00